SAI TEJA THOGITI

Email: saitejathogiti@gmail.com
Phone: +91-8520858615

.Net Technologies | Full Stack | 6 Years of Experience

Overview

A software engineer, over 6 years of experience in Analysis, Design, Development of software applications. Can be part of a fast-paced team, working in a globally collaborative environment. Collaborate with stake holders, other technical leaders on requirements and architecture. Design and develop software code, collaborating with developers and testers using the SCRUM process, to deliver iterative releases of product, with high quality expectations, and challenging timing of milestone delivery.

Key Experiences

- 6 years of experience in software development in .NET technologies, Sencha EXT JS and SQL Server.
- Breaking down features into granular level epics and develop detailed technical analysis and design specifications based on user stories. Provide estimates for delivery for the same.
- Document APIs and concepts related to development to help team members and other teams to effectively leverage work.
- Experience in designing and developing EXT JS application with layered architecture adhering to Mono repostyle.
- Implementing reactive UI component design focused on re-usability / scalability / supportability.
- Experience in migrating .Net framework-based applications into .Net Core
- Good working knowledge in Git, TFS, Pivotal Cloud Foundry, Urban Code Deploy, Jenkins, Azure Dev-ops, Splunk, App Dynamics, Channel Secure
- Good working knowledge in designing tables, stored procedures, functions, and triggers using SQL Server.
- Strong drive to learn and produce beautiful code adhering to SOLID principles following TDD methodologies.
- Domain experience: Banking and Finance, Insurance

Technical Skills

- Web Technologies: Ext JS, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Angular, TypeScript, Bootstrap
- NET/Microsoft technologies: .NET Framework, .NET Core, C#, Web Api, Entity Framework Core, ADO.Net
- Unit-testing & Logging: Splunk, Xunit, Moq, Karma, Jasmine
- Database: SQL server
- Cloud: Microsoft Azure, Cloud Foundry
- Methodologies: Agile, Test-Driven Development
- Tools: Splunk, App Dynamics, Jira, Git, TFS, Bit Bucket, Jenkins, Urban Code Deploy, Sonar Qube, Check Marx, Fortify, Black Duck

Education

- Bachelor of technology in Information Technology (2012- 2016) from Sreenidhi Institute of Science and Technology Engineering College, Hyderabad, India with 81.27%
- Board of Intermediate education, Telangana (2010- 2012) with 96.1%
- Board of Secondary Education, Telangana (2009- 2010) with 90.5%

Work Experience

- Currently working with Wells Fargo International Solutions as a Software Engineer from June 2019 till date.
- Worked with Capgemini as an Associate Consultant from August 2018 to June 2019
- Worked with Wipro Technologies as a Project Engineer from June 2016 to August 2018

Project Details

Technology Connection Business Intelligence Dashboard – Wells Fargo

TC Dashboard allows reporting for the managers of the TC Chat and Phone agents. Managers can track agents call/chat metrics, statistics of entire team, key performance metrics, attendance details, alert mechanism based on attendance threshold values. It allows them to be able to report on their productivity.

- Driven the discussions with Product Management team to understand requirements and convert them into technical specifications.
- Architecting the solution Implemented clean architecture and integrated Sencha UI in mono repo style.
- Integrated the system with Splunk logging achieving the goal of providing visual dashboards for logging.
- Created Dashboard with user friendly Ui designs using graphical representations of data in the form of Gauges, Charts, Grid views, Multiple grids.
- Created alert mechanism for managers and agents using email alerts functionality for daily attendance data.
- Handling Change requests, work requests to push code into different environments.
- Worked closely with Dev ops team on building CICD pipeline using Jenkins and deploy application in cloud foundry
- Integrated Sonar Qube, Check Marx, Black Duck, App Dynamics, Splunk logging, Channel Secure.
- Enhancing and optimizing the functionalities. Conducting peer review, team reviews on code.

Technology Connection Data – Wells Fargo

TC Data allows the technology connection managers to configure and manage metadata for reporting and dashboarding. This application has the capability to configure dynamic data in grid format and perform CRUD operations, filter and sort data, export to excel.

- Two level authentication using channel secure silent login and database level authentication using Active Directory groups
- Table level access and column level restrictions based on roles of the logged in user
- Created dynamic grids in Sencha Ext JS
- Created three different views Grid view, List view and Tab view in UI to compare and deal with multiple grids at the same time.
- Integrated Splunk logging, App Dynamics to view application logs and performance metrics in visual dashboards.
- Carrying out build, create release and deployment of code to lower environments
- Handling change and release management. Participating in Business Continuity Plan (BCP) events
- Worked on migrating application from .Net framework to .Net Core
- Worked on deployment in PCF cloud from Azure.
- Integrated Check Marx, Black Duck, Sonar Qube in CICD pipeline to maintain code quality, detect code smells and to avoid security risks.

Digital Messaging Preferences – Charles Schwab

The Preferences aims to provide retail clients with capability to select their preferred delivery channels for communications from Schwab. Clients will select from available channels of each category of messaging available.

• Analysis of the specifications provided by the clients. Provide estimates for the same.

- Discussion, design, research & development which helps in product enhancement
- Develop features following TDD approach.
- Attend 3-Amigo's meeting as part of sprint planning along with product owner and QA team.
- Attend scrum meetings daily and proactively communicate with concerned teams.
- Develop generic Components and Directives with Angular2 which can be used across various teams in the organization
- Enhancing and optimizing the functionalities. Conducting peer review, team reviews on code.

Personal Details

Full Name: Sai Teja ThogitiDOB: 30 August 1994

Sex: Male

Marital Status: Unmarried
Passport No.: P1175449
PAN No.: AWKPT0582E
Nationality: Indian
Address: Hyderabad

Declaration

I hereby declare that the information given above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Place: Hyderabad YOURS FAITHFULLY

Date: SAI TEJA THOGITI